[
    {
        "Question":"A surgeon makes a Pfannenstiel incision for access to the pelvic organs. He incises the abdominal wall down to and through the rectus sheath. He retracts the rectus abdominus muscles laterally from the midline to expose the:",
        "Option 1":"Linea alba",
        "Option 2":"Peritoneum",
        "Option 3":"Posterior rectus sheath",
        "Option 4":"Transversalis fascia",
        "Option 5":"Transversus abdominus muscle",
        "Correct Answer":"Transversalis fascia"
    },
    {
        "Question":"50 year old man prepared for exploration surgery. What is the layer where upper midline incision was done for exploration?",
        "Option 1":"Linea alba",
        "Option 2":"Linea semilunaris",
        "Option 3":"Fascia transversalis",
        "Option 4":"External oblique muscle",
        "Option 5":"Internal oblique muscle",
        "Correct Answer":"Linea alba"
    },
    {
        "Question":"65 year old man presented with an inguinoscrotal swelling in the right groin which is not tender. A cough impulse is elicited, at operation; an indirect inguinal hernia is repaired. The cremastric muscle is derived from which of the following part?",
        "Option 1":"External oblique aponeurosis",
        "Option 2":"Internal oblique aponeurosis",
        "Option 3":"Rectus abdominus muscle",
        "Option 4":"Rectus sheath",
        "Option 5":"Transversalis fascia",
        "Correct Answer":"Internal oblique aponeurosis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"40 year old man has inguinal hernia. Which of the following structures makes the posterior wall of inguinal canal?",
        "Option 1":"Conjoint tendon",
        "Option 2":"Internal oblique muscle",
        "Option 3":"External oblique muscle",
        "Option 4":"Transversus abdominus",
        "Option 5":"Cremasteric muscle",
        "Correct Answer":"Conjoint tendon"
    },
    {
        "Question":"45 year old man presents with a 3 X 4 cm swelling in the right groin which is non-tender, what is structure open during herniorrhaphy?",
        "Option 1":"External oblique aponeurosis",
        "Option 2":"Internal oblique muscle",
        "Option 3":"Conjoing tendon",
        "Option 4":"Fascia transversalis",
        "Option 5":"Peritoneum",
        "Correct Answer":"Peritoneum"
    },
    {
        "Question":"65 year old man presented with an inguinoscrotal swelling in the right groin which is not tender. A cough impulse is elicited, at operation; an indirect inguinal hernia is repaired. The external inguinal ring is a defect in which of the following abdominal muscles?",
        "Option 1":"External oblique aponeurosis",
        "Option 2":"External oblique muscle",
        "Option 3":"Internal oblique muscle",
        "Option 4":"Transversus abdominus muscle",
        "Option 5":"Transversalis fascia",
        "Correct Answer":"External oblique aponeurosis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"30 year old man has inguinal hernia. The surgeon during inguinal hernia repair found nerve in front of the cord after he opens external oblique aponeurosis, what is the nerve he found in front of the cord?",
        "Option 1":"Genital branch of genitofemoral nerve",
        "Option 2":"Femoral branch of genitofemoral nerve",
        "Option 3":"Ilioinguinal nerve",
        "Option 4":"Iliohypogastric nerve",
        "Option 5":"Femoral nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Ilioinguinal nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"55 year old presented with swelling in the right groin and it is non-tender. A cough impulse is elicited. At operation, indirect hernia is founded. From which structure listed does external spermatic fascia derive from?",
        "Option 1":"External oblique aponeurosis",
        "Option 2":"Internal oblique aponeurosis",
        "Option 3":"Fascia transversalis",
        "Option 4":"Rectus abdominus",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"External oblique aponeurosis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"55 year old presented with swelling in the right groin and it is non-tender. A cough impulse is elicited. At operation, indirect hernia is founded. From which structure listed does internal spermatic fascia derive from?",
        "Option 1":"Internal oblique muscle",
        "Option 2":"Internal oblique aponeurosis",
        "Option 3":"Fascia transversalis",
        "Option 4":"Transversus abdominus",
        "Option 5":"External oblique muscle",
        "Correct Answer":"Fascia transversalis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"75 year old presents with 3X4 swelling in the right groin and it is non-tender. A cough impulse is elicited. At operation, direct hernia is found, the hernial sac lies medial to which of the following?",
        "Option 1":"Iliohypogastric nerve",
        "Option 2":"Ilioinguinal nerve",
        "Option 3":"Inferior epigastric vessels",
        "Option 4":"Pubic tubercle",
        "Option 5":"Superficial epigastric vessels",
        "Correct Answer":"Inferior epigastric vessels"
    },
    {
        "Question":"75 year old man came to outpatient clinic and complained from bilateral groin swelling and diagnosed as bilateral direct hernia. Direct inguinal hernia is due to defect in which of the following layers?",
        "Option 1":"Rectus abdominus",
        "Option 2":"Fascia transversalis",
        "Option 3":"External oblique aponeurosis",
        "Option 4":"Internal oblique",
        "Option 5":"Transversus abdominus muscle",
        "Correct Answer":"Fascia transversalis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"45 year old man presents by bilateral inguinal hernia. The surgical team decides to repair this laparoscopically through extra-peritoneal approach. Through an infra-umbilical incision, the surgeon displace the inferior aspect of the rectus abdominus muscle and place a prothetic mesh into area to repair the hernia. Which structure will be posterior to the mesh?",
        "Option 1":"Peritoneum",
        "Option 2":"Internal oblique aponeurosis",
        "Option 3":"External oblique aponeurosis",
        "Option 4":"Posterior aspect of rectus sheath",
        "Option 5":"Bucks fascia",
        "Correct Answer":"Peritoneum"
    },
    {
        "Question":"45 year old man presents by unilateral inguinal hernia. The surgical team decides to repair it by open free tension technique. The put the mesh on which structure?",
        "Option 1":"Peritoneum",
        "Option 2":"Internal oblique aponeurosis",
        "Option 3":"External oblique aponeurosis",
        "Option 4":"Posterior aspect of rectus sheath",
        "Option 5":"Transversalis fascia",
        "Correct Answer":"Transversalis fascia"
    },
    {
        "Question":"During repair of inguinal hernia laparoscopic, we found nerve passing above external iliac vessels and enter the deep inguinal ring. What is the name of this nerve?",
        "Option 1":"Genital of genitofemoral",
        "Option 2":"Femoral of genitofemoral",
        "Option 3":"Ilioinguinal",
        "Option 4":"Lateral cutaneous nerve of the thigh",
        "Option 5":"Femoral",
        "Correct Answer":"Genital of genitofemoral"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 30 year old man presented by vaginal hydrocele. He decided to make operation for correction of hydrocele. During operation, dartos muscle is found to be one of the covering layers of scrotum. From which layer dartos muscle is derived from?",
        "Option 1":"Superficial fascial layer",
        "Option 2":"Cremasteric muscle",
        "Option 3":"Internal oblique muscle",
        "Option 4":"Peritoneum",
        "Option 5":"External oblique aponeurosis",
        "Correct Answer":"Superficial fascial layer"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 68 year old man presented with an inguinal hernia. During repair it was found to be direct hernia. Which of the following statements is correct regarding direct hernia?",
        "Option 1":"Inferior epigastric artery forms the lateral border",
        "Option 2":"Inferior epigastric artery forms the medial border",
        "Option 3":"Iliac artery forms the lateral border",
        "Option 4":"iliac artery forms the medial border",
        "Option 5":"none of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Inferior epigastric artery forms the lateral border"
    },
    {
        "Question":"a 68 year old man presented with inguinal hernia. During repair it was found to be direct hernia medial to inferior epigastric vessels. In which vein inferior epigastric vein drains?",
        "Option 1":"Internal iliac",
        "Option 2":"External iliac",
        "Option 3":"Superior mesenteric",
        "Option 4":"Inferior mesenteric",
        "Option 5":"Internal mammary",
        "Correct Answer":"External iliac"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 2 year old boy is referred because of an impalpable testis in the left scrotum. Which of the following positions describes and ectopic testis?",
        "Option 1":"At the deep inguinal ring",
        "Option 2":"At the root of the penis",
        "Option 3":"At the superficial inguinal ring",
        "Option 4":"In the inguinal canal",
        "Option 5":"In the upper part of the scrotum",
        "Correct Answer":"At the root of the penis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 2 year old boy is referred because of an impalpable testis in the left scrotum. Which of the following positions describes and ectopic testis?",
        "Option 1":"At the deep inguinal ring",
        "Option 2":"At the superficial inguinal pouch",
        "Option 3":"At the superficial inguinal ring",
        "Option 4":"In the inguinal canal",
        "Option 5":"In the upper part of the scrotum",
        "Correct Answer":"At the superficial inguinal pouch"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A year old child came to outpatient clinic because his parents noticed empty scrotum and diagnosed as undescended testis. Which structure of the listed below is the reason that testis descends to the scrotum?",
        "Option 1":"Gubernaculum",
        "Option 2":"Processus vaginalis",
        "Option 3":"Tunica vaginalis",
        "Option 4":"Tunica albuginea",
        "Option 5":"Cremasteric muscle",
        "Correct Answer":"Gubernaculum"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 2 year old child is referred due to empty scrotum. On examination, there is impalpable testis in the left inguinal canal and scrotum. What is the next step for this child?",
        "Option 1":"MRI abdomen",
        "Option 2":"CT abdomen",
        "Option 3":"Open exploration",
        "Option 4":"Laparoscopy",
        "Option 5":"Ultrasound",
        "Correct Answer":"Laparoscopy"
    },
    {
        "Question":"39 year old patient presented by penis fracture and hematoma is formed and spreads to lower abdomen, which fascia rupture allow spread of this blood?",
        "Option 1":"Dartos fascia",
        "Option 2":"Scarpa's fascia",
        "Option 3":"Camper's fascia",
        "Option 4":"Buck's fascia",
        "Option 5":"Colles fascia",
        "Correct Answer":"Buck's fascia"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the structures listed is the reason of inguinal hernia in pediatric age?",
        "Option 1":"Increase intra-abdominal pressure",
        "Option 2":"Gubernaculum",
        "Option 3":"Patent processes vaginalis",
        "Option 4":"Tunica vaginalis",
        "Option 5":"Weak abdominal muscles",
        "Correct Answer":"Patent processes vaginalis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 65 year old man presents with a non-tender swelling in the right hemi-srotum. At operation, the hydrocele sac is opened, and 400 ml of fluid is drained. Which anatomical structure surround the fluid?",
        "Option 1":"Dartos muscle",
        "Option 2":"Patent processus vaginalis",
        "Option 3":"Testicular capsule",
        "Option 4":"Tunica albuginea",
        "Option 5":"Tunica vaginalis",
        "Correct Answer":"Tunica vaginalis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 65 year old man presents with a non-tender swelling in the right hemi-srotum. At operation, the hydrocele sac is opened, and 400 ml of fluid is drained. Which layer is covering the testis after fluid is evacuated?",
        "Option 1":"Tunica vaginalis parietal layer",
        "Option 2":"Tunica albuginea",
        "Option 3":"Tunica vaginalis visceral layer",
        "Option 4":"Cremasteric muscle",
        "Option 5":"Dartos muscle",
        "Correct Answer":"Tunica vaginalis visceral layer"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Thoracic duct drains lymphatic form most of the body what is the level at which thoracic duct pass through the diaphragm?",
        "Option 1":"T8",
        "Option 2":"T10",
        "Option 3":"T12",
        "Option 4":"L1",
        "Option 5":"L4",
        "Correct Answer":"T12"
    },
    {
        "Question":"The aorta passes through the posterior mediastinum then enters the abdomen through the diaphragm. What is the level at which abdominal aorta pass through the diaphragm?",
        "Option 1":"T8",
        "Option 2":"T10",
        "Option 3":"T12",
        "Option 4":"L1",
        "Option 5":"L4",
        "Correct Answer":"T12"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 65 year old man presents with vomiting and weight loss. On examination he had palpable epigastric mass. The transpyloric plane lies at which vertebral level?",
        "Option 1":"T11",
        "Option 2":"T12",
        "Option 3":"L1",
        "Option 4":"L2",
        "Option 5":"L3",
        "Correct Answer":"L1"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 75 year old man presents with hepatomegaly and ascites. CT shows evidence of post hepatic portal hypertension. The inferior vena cava passes through the diaphragm at which vertebral level?",
        "Option 1":"T8",
        "Option 2":"T9",
        "Option 3":"T10",
        "Option 4":"T11",
        "Option 5":"T12",
        "Correct Answer":"T8"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the level of the aortic bifurcation?",
        "Option 1":"L1",
        "Option 2":"L2",
        "Option 3":"L3",
        "Option 4":"L4",
        "Option 5":"L5",
        "Correct Answer":"L4"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 75 year old man presents with esophageal reflux. Endoscopy confirms the presence of hiatus hernia. The esophagus passes through the diaphragm at which level",
        "Option 1":"T8",
        "Option 2":"T10",
        "Option 3":"T12",
        "Option 4":"L1",
        "Option 5":"L2",
        "Correct Answer":"T10"
    },
    {
        "Question":"a 75 year old man presents with DVT. CT confirms the presence of thrombus in his common iliac vein extending into inferior vena cava. Common iliac veins join to form the inferior vena cava at which vertebral level?",
        "Option 1":"L3",
        "Option 2":"L4",
        "Option 3":"L5",
        "Option 4":"S1",
        "Option 5":"S2",
        "Correct Answer":"L5"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 78 year old woman presents with urinary urgency and incontinence. The external urethral sphincter is innervated by which of the following nerve roots?",
        "Option 1":"L3,4,5",
        "Option 2":"L4,5,S1",
        "Option 3":"L5,S1,2",
        "Option 4":"S1,2,3",
        "Option 5":"S2,3,4",
        "Correct Answer":"S2,3,4"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the following structures passing through the diaphragmatic opening at T12?",
        "Option 1":"Azyzgos vein and thoracic duct",
        "Option 2":"Vagus nerve and esophagus",
        "Option 3":"IVC and phrenic nerve",
        "Option 4":"Ureter and gonadal vessels",
        "Option 5":"IVC only",
        "Correct Answer":"Azyzgos vein and thoracic duct"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the level of hilum of left kidney?",
        "Option 1":"L1",
        "Option 2":"L2",
        "Option 3":"L3",
        "Option 4":"L4",
        "Option 5":"L5",
        "Correct Answer":"L1"
    },
    {
        "Question":"35 year old man suffered from ureteric stone and presented by loin pain radiating to lower abdomen and genitalia. What is dermatome referred from ureteric pain?",
        "Option 1":"T8-10",
        "Option 2":"T10",
        "Option 3":"T11-L1",
        "Option 4":"L1-L3",
        "Option 5":"S2-S5",
        "Correct Answer":"T11-L1"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient presented with a vesicular rash between T8 to T10. What anatomical location of this dermatome?",
        "Option 1":"Costal margins",
        "Option 2":"Nipple",
        "Option 3":"Supra-pubic region",
        "Option 4":"Inguinal region",
        "Option 5":"Femoral region",
        "Correct Answer":"Costal margins"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Bullet going through junction of linea semilunaris and costal margin on the right side, which structure will be injured?",
        "Option 1":"GB",
        "Option 2":"Liver",
        "Option 3":"Right kidney",
        "Option 4":"Cecum",
        "Option 5":"Appendix",
        "Correct Answer":"GB"
    },
    {
        "Question":"34 years old female presented by calcular gall bladder with tenderness on right hypocondium. The site of cholecystitis tenderness is the meeting point between",
        "Option 1":"Right linea semilunaris and midaxillary line",
        "Option 2":"Costal margin and midaxillary line",
        "Option 3":"Right linea semilunaris and costal margin",
        "Option 4":"Linea alba and costal margin",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Right linea semilunaris and costal margin"
    },
    {
        "Question":"34 year old man after street fight arrived to emergency room suffering from stab wound on anterior chest right to recuts muscle. Which structure mostly affected?",
        "Option 1":"Mescolon of transverse colon",
        "Option 2":"Lung",
        "Option 3":"Pleura",
        "Option 4":"Right lobe of liver",
        "Option 5":"IVC",
        "Correct Answer":"Right lobe of liver"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A young man presented by right iliac fossa pain after central pain around umbilicus and diagnosed as appendicitis, why there is pain appears first in the central abdomen?",
        "Option 1":"Because appendicitis is swollen, and it contacts both anterior and posterior abdominal walls",
        "Option 2":"Because the pain is first conveyed by vagus parasympathetic fibers then somatic fibers in the parietal peritoneum of the abdomen",
        "Option 3":"Because the pain first conveyed by sympathetic fibers that enter the spinal cord at T10, then by somatic fibers in the paretal peritoneum in the abdominal walls",
        "Option 4":"Because the appendix first irritates the subcostal nerve then the ilioinguinal nerve",
        "Option 5":"Because the most sensitive fibers are the afferent sympathetic fibers that enter the spinal cord at T10 then the less sensitive fibres from the lower quadrant abdomen",
        "Correct Answer":"Because the pain first conveyed by sympathetic fibers that enter the spinal cord at T10, then by somatic fibers in the paretal peritoneum in the abdominal walls"
    },
    {
        "Question":"23 year old female has admitted to hospital due to acute appendicitis. Which of the following is the site of base of appendix where surgeon made their incision which is called Mcburney point?",
        "Option 1":"Point between the two third from the umbilicus and one third from anterior iliac spine",
        "Option 2":"Point between the one third from the umbilicus and two third from anterior iliac spine",
        "Option 3":"Midpoint between the anterior superior iliac spine and symphysis pubis",
        "Option 4":"midpoint between the anterior superior iliac spine and pubic tubercle",
        "Option 5":"midpoint between the posterior iliac spine and pubic tubercle",
        "Correct Answer":"Point between the two third from the umbilicus and one third from anterior iliac spine"
    },
    {
        "Question":"a 55 year old man presents with acute back pain following a severe road traffic accident. Neurological examination reveals lack of sensation of the umbilicus. What is the spinal level of neurological deficit likely to be?",
        "Option 1":"T8",
        "Option 2":"T9",
        "Option 3":"T10",
        "Option 4":"T11",
        "Option 5":"T12",
        "Correct Answer":"T10"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Young patient has appendicitis suffered from pain in umbilicus shifted or referred to right iliac fossa. Which nerve responsible for umbilical pian reaching to T10 segment of spinal cord?",
        "Option 1":"Thoracic splanchnic nerve",
        "Option 2":"Lumbar splanchnic nerve",
        "Option 3":"Vagus",
        "Option 4":"Iliohypogastric",
        "Option 5":"Ilioinguinal",
        "Correct Answer":"Thoracic splanchnic nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Patient has spinal cord injury at spinal cord segment S3. What is area of S3 dermatome territory?",
        "Option 1":"Perianal",
        "Option 2":"Ischial tuberosity",
        "Option 3":"Anterior scrotal",
        "Option 4":"Perineal",
        "Option 5":"Inguinal region",
        "Correct Answer":"Ischial tuberosity"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 3 year old boy is admitted to hospital with severe vomiting, radiographic examination reveals that he is suffering from annular pancreas. Which of these structures is constricted?",
        "Option 1":"First part of duodenum",
        "Option 2":"Second part duodenum",
        "Option 3":"Third part duodenum",
        "Option 4":"Proximal jejunum",
        "Option 5":"Pylorus of stomach",
        "Correct Answer":"Second part duodenum"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the following is not in immediate relation to 3rd part of duodenum?",
        "Option 1":"Right kidney",
        "Option 2":"Right ureter",
        "Option 3":"Psoas",
        "Option 4":"Aorta",
        "Option 5":"IVC",
        "Correct Answer":"Right kidney"
    },
    {
        "Question":"During operation for cancer colon. Surgeon found structure behind 2nd and 3rd part of duodenum. What is structure behind the 2nd and 3rd part of duodenum?",
        "Option 1":"Ureter",
        "Option 2":"Gonadal vessels",
        "Option 3":"Kidney",
        "Option 4":"IVC",
        "Option 5":"Aorta",
        "Correct Answer":"IVC"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Common bile duct unit with pancreatic duct and opening in the small bowel by ampulla of vater. Ampulla of Vater opening in which part?",
        "Option 1":"In the posteriomedial part of the 1st part of duodenum",
        "Option 2":"In the posteriomedial part of the 2nd  part of duodenum",
        "Option 3":"In the posteriomedial part of the 3rd part of duodenum",
        "Option 4":"In the posteriomedial part of the proximal jejunum",
        "Option 5":"In the posteriomedial part of the distal jejunum",
        "Correct Answer":"In the posteriomedial part of the 2nd  part of duodenum"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 66 year old man has pancreatic head cancer. In operation which structure lies anterior to head of pancreas?",
        "Option 1":"Pylorus of stomach",
        "Option 2":"Portal vein",
        "Option 3":"Hepatic artery",
        "Option 4":"Common bile duct",
        "Option 5":"IVC",
        "Correct Answer":"Pylorus of stomach"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What helps surgeon identify uncinate process of pancreas in the operation?",
        "Option 1":"Lies anterior to inferior mesenteric artery",
        "Option 2":"Lies anterior of superior mesenteric vessels",
        "Option 3":"Lies posterior to superior mesenteric vessels",
        "Option 4":"Lies posterior to aorta",
        "Option 5":"Lies anterior to portal vein",
        "Correct Answer":"Lies posterior to superior mesenteric vessels"
    },
    {
        "Question":"After RTA, 30 year old patient has abdominal trauma. After exploration, surgeon found that bleeding come from porta hepatis so he does pringle maneuvar but still persistent bleeding. Which structure behind his finger in pringle manuver?",
        "Option 1":"Common hepatic duct",
        "Option 2":"IVC",
        "Option 3":"Right gastroepiploic artery",
        "Option 4":"Common hepatic artery",
        "Option 5":"Portal vein",
        "Correct Answer":"IVC"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Lesser sac is potential space known for intra-abdominal collections. Which of the following statements regarding lesser sac is true?",
        "Option 1":"Inferior vena cava forms the lateral border",
        "Option 2":"The portal vein is in the anterior free edge",
        "Option 3":"The stomach forms the posterior wall",
        "Option 4":"Cystic duct is in the anterior free edge",
        "Option 5":"Left gastric artery is in the posterior aspect",
        "Correct Answer":"The portal vein is in the anterior free edge"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the following structures present at free border in the lesser omentum of stomach?",
        "Option 1":"Common hepatic duct",
        "Option 2":"IVC",
        "Option 3":"Right gastroepiploic artery",
        "Option 4":"Short gastric artery",
        "Option 5":"Left gastric artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Common hepatic duct"
    },
    {
        "Question":"During making laparoscopic cholecystectomy, we should identify the Calot triangle. What is the medial boundary of Calot triangle?",
        "Option 1":"Hepatic artery",
        "Option 2":"Cystic duct",
        "Option 3":"Cystic artery",
        "Option 4":"Hepatic duct",
        "Option 5":"Common bile duct",
        "Correct Answer":"Hepatic duct"
    },
    {
        "Question":"During making laparoscopic cholecystectomy, we should identify the Calot triangle. All of the following belong to calot\u2019s triangle as boundaries or contents except?",
        "Option 1":"Cystic artery",
        "Option 2":"Cystic duct",
        "Option 3":"Lower border of liver",
        "Option 4":"Common bile duct",
        "Option 5":"Hepatic duct",
        "Correct Answer":"Common bile duct"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the content of callot triangle which is ligated during cholecystectomy?",
        "Option 1":"Cystic artery",
        "Option 2":"Hepatic artery",
        "Option 3":"Cystic duct",
        "Option 4":"Common hepatic duct",
        "Option 5":"Hepatic duct",
        "Correct Answer":"Cystic artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"23 year old man stabbed to anterior chest below right 9 costal margins. In emergency department, abdominal ultrasound shows large amounts of intra-peritoneal blood. Which of the following is mostly injured?",
        "Option 1":"Right lower lobe of lung",
        "Option 2":"Right pleura",
        "Option 3":"Left lobe of liver",
        "Option 4":"Right lobe of liver",
        "Option 5":"IVC",
        "Correct Answer":"Right lobe of liver"
    },
    {
        "Question":"23 year old man stabbed to chest 10 cm below the right nipple. In emergency department, abdominal ultrasound show large amount of intra-peritoneal blood and detected liver trauma in CT abdomen, which of the following is supplied by right hepatic artery?",
        "Option 1":"Right lobe of liver",
        "Option 2":"Right lobe of liver and caudate lobe",
        "Option 3":"Right lobe of liver and quadrate lobe",
        "Option 4":"Right lobe, caudate and quadrate",
        "Option 5":"Left lobe of the liver",
        "Correct Answer":"Right lobe of liver and caudate lobe"
    },
    {
        "Question":"60 year old patient presented by hematemesis and made upper endoscope and diagnosed as esophageal varices, the anastomosis in lower esophagus is made between which vessels?",
        "Option 1":"Left gastic vein and short gastric vein",
        "Option 2":"Left gastric vein and esophageal veins",
        "Option 3":"Right gastric vein and esophageal veins",
        "Option 4":"Left gastroepiploic and esophageal veins",
        "Option 5":"Right gastroepiploic and esophageal veins",
        "Correct Answer":"Left gastric vein and esophageal veins"
    },
    {
        "Question":"60 year old patient presented by hematemesis and made upper endoscope and diagnosed as esophageal varices, the anastomosis in lower esophagus is made between esophageal veins and which vein?",
        "Option 1":"Left gastric vein",
        "Option 2":"Short gastric vein",
        "Option 3":"Right gastric vein",
        "Option 4":"Left gastroepiploic",
        "Option 5":"Right gastroepiploic",
        "Correct Answer":"Left gastric vein"
    },
    {
        "Question":"63 year old is admitted with hematemesis. An upper GIT endoscope is performed and ulcer is found in greater curventure of anterior stomach between antrum and body of stomach, what is the source of bleeding?",
        "Option 1":"Short gastric",
        "Option 2":"Left gastroepiploic",
        "Option 3":"Right gastroepiploic",
        "Option 4":"Left gastric",
        "Option 5":"Right gastric",
        "Correct Answer":"Right gastroepiploic"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the blood supply of the lower 3rd of esophagus",
        "Option 1":"Inferior thyroid artery",
        "Option 2":"Thoracic aorta",
        "Option 3":"Left gastric artery",
        "Option 4":"Right gastroepiploic",
        "Option 5":"Gastroduodenal artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Left gastric artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"30 year old is admitted with hematemesis. An upper GIT endoscope is performed and posterior perforating duodenal ulcer is founded, what is the most common artery to be injured?",
        "Option 1":"Short gastric",
        "Option 2":"Left gastric",
        "Option 3":"Left gastroepiploic artery",
        "Option 4":"Gastroduodenal artery",
        "Option 5":"Right gastroepiploic artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Gastroduodenal artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"The greater curvature of stomach has gastroepiploic arterial supply. Right gastroepiploic artery is a branch from?",
        "Option 1":"Cystic artery",
        "Option 2":"Celiac artery",
        "Option 3":"Right gastric",
        "Option 4":"Gastroduodenal artery",
        "Option 5":"Left gastric",
        "Correct Answer":"Gastroduodenal artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A surgeon is carrying out an elective splenectomy for congenital spheriocytosis. Which structure will be divided in order to mobilize the spleen from the posterior abdominal wall?",
        "Option 1":"Gastrosplenic ligament",
        "Option 2":"Lesser omentum",
        "Option 3":"Linorenal ligament",
        "Option 4":"Phrenocolic ligament",
        "Option 5":"Short gastric vessels",
        "Correct Answer":"Linorenal ligament"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient undergoes splenectomy after trauma. During operation the surgeon was due to ligate the splenic artery. What is the structure most likely to be injured during this step?",
        "Option 1":"Tail of the pancreas",
        "Option 2":"Fundus of the stomach",
        "Option 3":"Pancreatic duct",
        "Option 4":"Phrenco-colic ligament",
        "Option 5":"Small intestine",
        "Correct Answer":"Tail of the pancreas"
    },
    {
        "Question":"During splenectomy operation, short gastric arteries are ligated. Which structure at risk of direct damage during their ligation?",
        "Option 1":"Fundus of stomach",
        "Option 2":"Tail of pancreas",
        "Option 3":"Head of pancreas",
        "Option 4":"Left kidney",
        "Option 5":"Left suprarenal",
        "Correct Answer":"Fundus of stomach"
    },
    {
        "Question":"34 year old man has aneurysm of splenic artery. Which structure affected other than spleen?",
        "Option 1":"Head of pancreas",
        "Option 2":"Fundus of stomach",
        "Option 3":"Colon",
        "Option 4":"Duodenum",
        "Option 5":"Small bowel",
        "Correct Answer":"Fundus of stomach"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Patient has abdominal free fluid collection in the lowest part of the peritoneal cavity due to perforated appendix. At operation while the patient is supine, in which of the following space will the fluid collect first?",
        "Option 1":"Hepatorenal pouch",
        "Option 2":"Left anterior subphrenic space",
        "Option 3":"Lesser sac",
        "Option 4":"Right paracolic gutter",
        "Option 5":"Right anterior subphrenic space",
        "Correct Answer":"Hepatorenal pouch"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the commonest site of abdomen for fluid collection following perforated appendix or post appendectomy operation?",
        "Option 1":"Right subhepatic",
        "Option 2":"Left subhepatic",
        "Option 3":"Morrison space",
        "Option 4":"Pelvis",
        "Option 5":"Lesser sac",
        "Correct Answer":"Pelvis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"65 years old patient with perforated posterior gastric ulcer. What is the site of fluid collection will appear?",
        "Option 1":"Omental bursa",
        "Option 2":"Right paracolic gutter",
        "Option 3":"Hepatorenal pouch",
        "Option 4":"Infracolic gutter",
        "Option 5":"Greater sac",
        "Correct Answer":"Omental bursa"
    },
    {
        "Question":"30 year old female presented by abdominal pain due to rupture ovarian cyst in which site the fluid collection will mostly appear?",
        "Option 1":"Hepatorenal pouch",
        "Option 2":"Rectovesical pouch",
        "Option 3":"Rectouterine pouch",
        "Option 4":"Vesicouterine pouch",
        "Option 5":"Omental bursa",
        "Correct Answer":"Rectouterine pouch"
    },
    {
        "Question":"45 year old patient has chronic pancreatitis on angiography, there is aneurysm of a tortious vessel which directly arises from the celiac trunk. Which structure does this vessels supply?",
        "Option 1":"Head of pancreas",
        "Option 2":"Left kidney hilum",
        "Option 3":"1st part of duodenum",
        "Option 4":"Jejunum",
        "Option 5":"Fundus of stomach",
        "Correct Answer":"Fundus of stomach"
    },
    {
        "Question":"An 82 year old man has complete occlusion of his inferior mesenteric artery on angiography but no symptoms or signs of colonic ischemia. Which of the following arteries is the most likely additional source of blood supply to the territory of the inferior mesenteric artery?",
        "Option 1":"Left colic artery",
        "Option 2":"Left gastroepiploic artery",
        "Option 3":"Middle colic artery",
        "Option 4":"Splenic artery",
        "Option 5":"Superior rectal artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Middle colic artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"75 year old woman, who has a carcinoma of the upper rectum, undergoes anterior resection, the arterial supply of upper rectum arises from which of the following?",
        "Option 1":"Coeliac artery",
        "Option 2":"Ileocolic artery",
        "Option 3":"Inferior mesenteric artery",
        "Option 4":"Internal iliac artery",
        "Option 5":"Superior mesenteric artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Inferior mesenteric artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 65 year old man is undergoing an abdominal aortogram. A stenosis is demonstrated in a lateral aortic branch, arising at the level of the body of the second lumbar vertebra. The stenosed vessel is most likely to be the:",
        "Option 1":"Celiac artery",
        "Option 2":"Inferior mesenteric artery",
        "Option 3":"Left renal artery",
        "Option 4":"Second left lumbar artery",
        "Option 5":"Superior mesenteric artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Second left lumbar artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient is found to have an ischemic left colon. Which artery arising from the aorta at around the level of L3 is most likely accounted for this situation?",
        "Option 1":"Superior mesenteric artery",
        "Option 2":"Inferior mesenteric artery",
        "Option 3":"Superior rectal artery",
        "Option 4":"Ileocolic artery",
        "Option 5":"Middle colic artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Inferior mesenteric artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Bleeding per rectum in old gentleman, colonoscopy revealed it is around sigmoid colon planned for angioemblizaition. Which vessel should the interventionist enter to stop bleed?",
        "Option 1":"Right colic artery",
        "Option 2":"Left colic artery",
        "Option 3":"Middle colic artery",
        "Option 4":"Ileocolic artery",
        "Option 5":"Appendicular artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Left colic artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 60 year old man is undergoing an abdominal aortogram due to lower GIT bleeding. What is the most inferior anterior branch?",
        "Option 1":"Inferior mesenteric artery",
        "Option 2":"Median sacral",
        "Option 3":"Superior mesenteric artery",
        "Option 4":"Renal artery",
        "Option 5":"Celiac artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Inferior mesenteric artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 65 year old man is undergoing an abdominal aortogram due to lower GIT bleeding. What is the branch of the aorta that leaves approximately 1 cm below the celiac axis?",
        "Option 1":"Superior mesenteric artery",
        "Option 2":"Renal artery",
        "Option 3":"Inferior mesenteric artery",
        "Option 4":"Gonadal artery",
        "Option 5":"Iliac artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Superior mesenteric artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 60 year old man is undergoing an abdominal aortogram. What is the most inferior single branch from the aorta?",
        "Option 1":"Median sacral",
        "Option 2":"Inferior mesenteric",
        "Option 3":"Superior mesenteric",
        "Option 4":"Renal",
        "Option 5":"Celiac",
        "Correct Answer":"Median sacral"
    },
    {
        "Question":"60 year old patient presented by hematemesis and diagnosed having portal vein hypertension. The portal vein formed by union of which veins?",
        "Option 1":"Superior mesenteric vein and inferior mesenteric vein",
        "Option 2":"Superior mesenteric vein and splenic vein",
        "Option 3":"Inferior mesenteric vein and splenic vein",
        "Option 4":"Left gastric vein and splenic vein",
        "Option 5":"Right gastric vein and splenic vein",
        "Correct Answer":"Superior mesenteric vein and splenic vein"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Surgeon doing right hemi-colectomy for removal of cancer cecum. In right hemi-colectomy, what is the artery should be ligated?",
        "Option 1":"Ileocolic artery",
        "Option 2":"Middle colic artery",
        "Option 3":"Left colic artery",
        "Option 4":"inferior mesenteric artery",
        "Option 5":"left colic artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Ileocolic artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"what is the most common part of the following is susceptible to colonic ischemia?",
        "Option 1":"Right colon transverse",
        "Option 2":"Rectosigmoid",
        "Option 3":"Left colon",
        "Option 4":"Splenic flexure",
        "Option 5":"Hepatic flexure",
        "Correct Answer":"Splenic flexure"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the location of the celiac autonomic plexus?",
        "Option 1":"Anterolateral of aorta",
        "Option 2":"Posterolateral of aorta",
        "Option 3":"Anterolateral of IVC",
        "Option 4":"posterolateral of IVC",
        "Option 5":"in front of inferior mesenteric artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Anterolateral of aorta"
    },
    {
        "Question":"while doing hernia repair, surgeon found inferior epigastric vessels is medial to indirect inguinal hernia. From which artery inferior epigastric artery originated from?",
        "Option 1":"External iliac artery",
        "Option 2":"Internal iliac artery",
        "Option 3":"Femoral artery",
        "Option 4":"Inferior mesenteric artery",
        "Option 5":"Superior mesenteric artery",
        "Correct Answer":"External iliac artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"From which superior gluteal artery is originated from?",
        "Option 1":"External iliac artery",
        "Option 2":"Internal iliac artery",
        "Option 3":"femoral artery",
        "Option 4":"inferior mesenteric artery",
        "Option 5":"superior mesenteric artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Internal iliac artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"a 50 year old patient is to undergo elective laparoscopic right hemi-colectomy for a cecal tumor; a segment of bowel covering the cecum was held and retracted by a grasper. How will you differentiate the jejunum from ilium during laparoscopy?",
        "Option 1":"Long arterial arcade of mesentery",
        "Option 2":"Long vasa recta of the mesentery",
        "Option 3":"Sacculation and epindices epiplica",
        "Option 4":"Payer patches",
        "Option 5":"Walking doctor from right to left to reach the ileocecal valve",
        "Correct Answer":"Long vasa recta of the mesentery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 28 year old man presents with an ischiorectal abscess. Where is this abscess cavity likely to be sited?",
        "Option 1":"Above levator ani",
        "Option 2":"Between external and internal anal sphincter",
        "Option 3":"Lateral to the obturator internus",
        "Option 4":"Medial to the internal anal sphincter",
        "Option 5":"Medial to the pudendal",
        "Correct Answer":"Medial to the pudendal"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient undergoes surgery for incision and drainage of ischiorectal abscess. What is the palpating finger feel on the medial margin of the abscess cavity?",
        "Option 1":"Internal anal sphincter",
        "Option 2":"Ischial tuberosity",
        "Option 3":"Levator ani",
        "Option 4":"Obturator internus muscle",
        "Option 5":"Pudendal canal",
        "Correct Answer":"Levator ani"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 42 year old multiparous woman is admitted to the emergency department due to pelvic discomfort. The duty gynaecologist diagnosis uterine prolapse. Which anatomical structure gives significant direct support to the uterus?",
        "Option 1":"Cervical ligaments",
        "Option 2":"Broad ligament",
        "Option 3":"Round ligament",
        "Option 4":"Transverse perineal muscles",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Transverse perineal muscles"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Male pelvis differs from the female one by all of the following except",
        "Option 1":"The female pelvis is wider and shallower then male",
        "Option 2":"The female inlet is rounded or oval while the male is apple in shape",
        "Option 3":"Supra-pubic angle is acute in female while male is large",
        "Option 4":"The bone is lighter in female than in male",
        "Option 5":"Coccyx is straight in female while in male is curved",
        "Correct Answer":"Supra-pubic angle is acute in female while male is large"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A senior registrar did PR examination for a patient and he felt something laterally 4 cm form anus. What anatomical structure is it?",
        "Option 1":"Bladder dome",
        "Option 2":"Bladder base",
        "Option 3":"Prostate",
        "Option 4":"Puborectalis muscle",
        "Option 5":"Vas deferens",
        "Correct Answer":"Puborectalis muscle"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A doctor examine female for pelvic pain. What is the structure that felt in PV examination anteriorly at the level of cervix?",
        "Option 1":"Dome of the bladder",
        "Option 2":"Base of the bladder",
        "Option 3":"Puborectalis",
        "Option 4":"Ischiorectal fossa",
        "Option 5":"Anal sphincter",
        "Correct Answer":"Base of the bladder"
    },
    {
        "Question":"After resection of rectal tumor, a patient experiences erectile dysfunction. Which of the following nerves is most likely to have been damaged in surgery?",
        "Option 1":"Genitofemoral nerve",
        "Option 2":"Lumbosacral plexus",
        "Option 3":"Pelvic splanchnic nerves",
        "Option 4":"Perineal branch of S4",
        "Option 5":"Pudendal nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Pelvic splanchnic nerves"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Female undergo ovarian surgery then she develops paraesthesia over thigh, what is the most accepted nerve to be injured ?",
        "Option 1":"Genitofemoral nerve",
        "Option 2":"Ilioinguinal nerve",
        "Option 3":"Obturator nerve",
        "Option 4":"Femoral nerve",
        "Option 5":"Iliohypogastric nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Obturator nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the most common nerve to be injured in gridiron incision for appendectomy?",
        "Option 1":"Genitofemoral",
        "Option 2":"Ilioinguinal",
        "Option 3":"Obturator",
        "Option 4":"Femoral nerve",
        "Option 5":"Obturator nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Ilioinguinal"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 70 year old man complains of persistent numbness since an inguinal hernia repair one year previously. The numbness affects the top of the scrotum, root of penis, and a small area below the medial part of the inguinal ligament. Which nerve is likely to have been damaged?",
        "Option 1":"Femoral branch of genitofemoral nerve",
        "Option 2":"Genital branch of genitofemoral nerve",
        "Option 3":"Iliohypogastric nerve",
        "Option 4":"Ilioinguinal nerve",
        "Option 5":"Medial cutaneous branch of the femoral nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Ilioinguinal nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 50 year old woman presents with a history of fecal incontinence over the past few years she had a prolonged and difficult first stage of labor 20 years previously. Physical examination revealed that a relatively lax anal sphincter. Which nerve is likely to have been damaged in labor?",
        "Option 1":"Autonomic nerves to the rectum",
        "Option 2":"Genitofemoral nerve",
        "Option 3":"Lumbosacral trunk",
        "Option 4":"Obturator nerve",
        "Option 5":"Pudendal nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Pudendal nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 70-year-old man undergoes transurethral resection of bladder TURBT. The tumor lies over the lateral side wall of the bladder just above the opening of the right ureteric orifice. Use of the diathermy suddenly causes the patient to 'kick' because of contraction of the hip adductors muscles. Which nerve has been stimulated?",
        "Option 1":"Femoral nerve",
        "Option 2":"Genitofemoral nerve",
        "Option 3":"Lateral femoral cutaneous nerve",
        "Option 4":"Obturator nerve",
        "Option 5":"Sciatic nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Obturator nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 50-year-old woman presents with a history of fecal incontinence over the past few years. She had a prolonged and difficult first stage of labor 20 years previously. Physical examination reveals a relatively lax anal sphincter. Which nerve is likely to have been damaged in labor?",
        "Option 1":"Autonomic nerves to the rectum",
        "Option 2":"Genitofemoral nerve",
        "Option 3":"Lumbosacral trunk",
        "Option 4":"Obturator nerve",
        "Option 5":"Pudendal nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Pudendal nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"During Transurethral resection of prostate and with using diathermy, which nerve is  most likely to be stimulated?",
        "Option 1":"Pudendal nerve",
        "Option 2":"Obturator nerve",
        "Option 3":"Femoral nerve",
        "Option 4":"Genitofemoral nerve",
        "Option 5":"ilioinguinal nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Obturator nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is common Injury happened during transurethral resection of prostate?",
        "Option 1":"Retrograde ejaculation",
        "Option 2":"erectile dysfunction",
        "Option 3":"inguinal parenthesis",
        "Option 4":"obturator nerve injury",
        "Option 5":"femoral nerve injury",
        "Correct Answer":"Retrograde ejaculation"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the nerve emerging from superior part of psoas muscle?",
        "Option 1":"Ilioinguinal nerve",
        "Option 2":"Iliohypogastric",
        "Option 3":"Femoral nerve",
        "Option 4":"Genitofemoral nerve",
        "Option 5":"Obturator nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Genitofemoral nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"During vaginal delivery, the obstetrician needs to do episiotomy. Which nerve is  blocked during episiotomy?",
        "Option 1":"internal pudendal nerve",
        "Option 2":"Obturator nerve",
        "Option 3":"ilioinguinal nerve",
        "Option 4":"Genitofemnoral nerve",
        "Option 5":"Lumbosacral trunk",
        "Correct Answer":"internal pudendal nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"During vaginal delivery, the obstetrician needs to do episiotomy. What is the  landmark for pudendal nerve block?",
        "Option 1":"Ischial tuberosity",
        "Option 2":"Ischeal spine",
        "Option 3":"Sacrotuburous ligament",
        "Option 4":"Sacroiliac joint",
        "Option 5":"Sacrum",
        "Correct Answer":"Ischeal spine"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the main nerve root supply pelvic diaphragm muscle?",
        "Option 1":"S1",
        "Option 2":"S2",
        "Option 3":"S3",
        "Option 4":"S4",
        "Option 5":"S5",
        "Correct Answer":"S3"
    },
    {
        "Question":"70 years old man has Gastric fundus cancer, where to search for lymphatic spread?",
        "Option 1":"Celiac",
        "Option 2":"Para-aortic",
        "Option 3":"Superior mesenteric",
        "Option 4":"Portal",
        "Option 5":"Inguinal",
        "Correct Answer":"Celiac"
    },
    {
        "Question":"40 years old man has testicular mass suspected cancer with enlarged lymph nodes.  What is the Lymphatic drainage of the testis?",
        "Option 1":"Para-aortic LN",
        "Option 2":"Superficial inguinal L.N",
        "Option 3":"Deep inguinal LN",
        "Option 4":"Superficial inguinal",
        "Option 5":"Internal ilac",
        "Correct Answer":"Para-aortic LN"
    },
    {
        "Question":"70 years old man with right scrotal ulcer. What is lymphatic drainage of scrotal ulcer?",
        "Option 1":"Deep inguinal",
        "Option 2":"Lumbar",
        "Option 3":"Para-aortic",
        "Option 4":"Superficial inguinal",
        "Option 5":"Internal iliac",
        "Correct Answer":"Superficial inguinal"
    },
    {
        "Question":"50 years old presented by blood spots in her panty. After examination, there is mass  in vulva. What is lymphatic drainage of vulva cancer?",
        "Option 1":"Deep inguinal",
        "Option 2":"Lumbar",
        "Option 3":"Para-aortic",
        "Option 4":"Superficial inguinal",
        "Option 5":"Internal iliac",
        "Correct Answer":"Superficial inguinal"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Superficial inguinal lymph nodes enlargement. By visual examination no lesion on  scrotum and penis. What may be origin of metastasis?",
        "Option 1":"Glans penis",
        "Option 2":"Anal canal",
        "Option 3":"Rectum",
        "Option 4":"Testis",
        "Option 5":"Prostate",
        "Correct Answer":"Anal canal"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is lymphatic drainage of inferior part of anal canal or squamous cell cancer of  the anal canal below dentate line or anal verge cancer?",
        "Option 1":"Deep inguinal",
        "Option 2":"Lumbar",
        "Option 3":"Para-aortic",
        "Option 4":"Superficial inguinal",
        "Option 5":"Internal iliac",
        "Correct Answer":"Superficial inguinal"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the lymph drainage of ovaries?",
        "Option 1":"External and Internal iliac LN",
        "Option 2":"Para-aortic LN",
        "Option 3":"Inguinal LN",
        "Option 4":"Obturator LN",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Para-aortic LN"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the lymph drainage of cervix of uterus other than internal iliac lymph nodes?",
        "Option 1":"External and sacral lymph nodes",
        "Option 2":"Para-aortic lymph nodes",
        "Option 3":"Superficial inguinal lymph nodes",
        "Option 4":"Obturator lymph nodes",
        "Option 5":"Deep inguinal lymph nodes",
        "Correct Answer":"External and sacral lymph nodes"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the first site of lymph drainage of prostate carcer?",
        "Option 1":"External iliac LN",
        "Option 2":"Para-aortic LN",
        "Option 3":"Superficial inguinal L.N",
        "Option 4":"Obturator LN",
        "Option 5":"Deep inguinal LN",
        "Correct Answer":"Obturator LN"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 65 old Female with several hard irregular lymph nodes in both femoral triangles. History confirms that she has occasional spot of fresh blood in under clothes in the past three months. Clinical examination falls to reveal any other lymphadenopathy, which of the following is most likely the diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Carcinoma of the bladder",
        "Option 2":"Carcinoma of cervix of uterus",
        "Option 3":"Carcinoma of endometrium",
        "Option 4":"Carcinoma of rectum",
        "Option 5":"Carcinoma of the vulva",
        "Correct Answer":"Carcinoma of the vulva"
    },
    {
        "Question":"60 years old presented by mass on glans penis suspected to be squamous cell cancer. What is the lymphatic drainage of glans penis?",
        "Option 1":"External iliac LN",
        "Option 2":"Para-aortic LN",
        "Option 3":"Superficial inguinal L.N",
        "Option 4":"Obturator LN",
        "Option 5":"Deep inguinal",
        "Correct Answer":"Deep inguinal"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 56 years patient presented with irreducible phimosis to the surgical outpatient and was found to have a fungating mass over his glans penis, his superficial inguinal lymph nodes were enlarged. What is the most likely diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Squamous cell Cancer",
        "Option 2":"Adenocarcinoma",
        "Option 3":"Transitional cell carcinoma",
        "Option 4":"HPV infection",
        "Option 5":"Lichen Planus",
        "Correct Answer":"Squamous cell Cancer"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 65-year-old man presents with hematuria and left loin pain. Computerized tomography demonstrates a left renal tumor. He undergoes a left radical nephrectomy. Where does the left renal artery lie?",
        "Option 1":"Anterior to the left gonadal vein",
        "Option 2":"Anterior to the left renal vein",
        "Option 3":"Anterior to the splenic vein",
        "Option 4":"Posterior to the left renal vein",
        "Option 5":"Superior to the superior mesenteric artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Posterior to the left renal vein"
    },
    {
        "Question":"122. A 67-year-old man has an abdominal aortic aneurysm which displaces the left renal  vein. Which branch of the aorta is most likely to affect at this level?",
        "Option 1":"Inferior mesenteric artery",
        "Option 2":"Superior mesenteric artery",
        "Option 3":"Coeliac axis",
        "Option 4":"Testicular artery",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Superior mesenteric artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"75 years old man underwent an anterior resection of rectal cancer, where does the  ureter normally lie in relation to gonadal vessels at pelvic brim?",
        "Option 1":"Anterior",
        "Option 2":"Lateral",
        "Option 3":"Posterior",
        "Option 4":"Medial",
        "Option 5":"Posterolateral",
        "Correct Answer":"Medial"
    },
    {
        "Question":"75 years old man underwent an anterior resection of rectal cancer, what is the point  of entry of the ureter to the pelvis?",
        "Option 1":"Ischio iliac joint",
        "Option 2":"bifurcation of common iliac vessel",
        "Option 3":"Anterior to internal iliac artery",
        "Option 4":"Sacroiliac joint",
        "Option 5":"Ischial spine",
        "Correct Answer":"bifurcation of common iliac vessel"
    },
    {
        "Question":"60-year-old man undergoes cystectomy for a bladder carcinoma. During surgery, the  ureters are identified. On which region of the bladder do the ureters pierce the bladder  wall?",
        "Option 1":"Anterior surface",
        "Option 2":"Apex",
        "Option 3":"Lateral surfaces",
        "Option 4":"Neck",
        "Option 5":"Posterior surface",
        "Correct Answer":"Posterior surface"
    },
    {
        "Question":"The posterior bed of kidney includes all the following except:",
        "Option 1":"Iliacus muscle",
        "Option 2":"Psoas muscle",
        "Option 3":"Transversus abdominus",
        "Option 4":"Quadratus lumborum",
        "Option 5":"Diaphragm",
        "Correct Answer":"Iliacus muscle"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Posterior relation of the kidney includes which of the following?",
        "Option 1":"Psoas muscle",
        "Option 2":"Peritoneum",
        "Option 3":"Liver",
        "Option 4":"Hepatic flexure",
        "Option 5":"Gonadal vessels",
        "Correct Answer":"Psoas muscle"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is most relevant anterior relation-of right suprarenal gland?",
        "Option 1":"IVC",
        "Option 2":"SVC",
        "Option 3":"SMA",
        "Option 4":"IMA",
        "Option 5":"Aorta",
        "Correct Answer":"IVC"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Patient with supra renal mass going came for surgical removal. In operation, left supra  renal gland lower pole medially corresponds to?",
        "Option 1":"celiac ganglion",
        "Option 2":"left renal vein",
        "Option 3":"left crus of diaphragm",
        "Option 4":"Body of pancreas",
        "Option 5":"Splenic vessels",
        "Correct Answer":"left renal vein"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Where the left renal vein drains to?",
        "Option 1":"IVC",
        "Option 2":"Left gonadal vein",
        "Option 3":"Left middle suprarenal vein",
        "Option 4":"Inferior mesenteric vein",
        "Option 5":"Superior mesenteric vein",
        "Correct Answer":"IVC"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Where the left testicular vein drains into?",
        "Option 1":"Inferior vena cava",
        "Option 2":"Left renal vein",
        "Option 3":"Left suprarenal",
        "Option 4":"Inferior mesenteric vein",
        "Option 5":"Superior mesenteric vein",
        "Correct Answer":"Left renal vein"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 65 years old man presents with hematuria and left loin pain. CT abdomen  demonstrate left renal tumor, He undergoes left radical nephrectomy. Where does the left  renal vein lie?",
        "Option 1":"Anterior to aorta",
        "Option 2":"Anterior to splenic vein",
        "Option 3":"Posterior to left renal artery",
        "Option 4":"Posterior to left ureter",
        "Option 5":"Superior to superior mesenteric artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Anterior to aorta"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is true relation to right renal artery?",
        "Option 1":"Posterior to renal pelvis",
        "Option 2":"Posterior to superior mesenteric artery",
        "Option 3":"Posterior to IVC",
        "Option 4":"Anterior to renal vein",
        "Option 5":"Anterior to aorta",
        "Correct Answer":"Posterior to IVC"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A man with left loin colicky pain. Imaging show stone impaction at the Vesicoureteral  junction where is it visible?",
        "Option 1":"Ischial tuberosity",
        "Option 2":"Ischial spine",
        "Option 3":"Sacroiliac joint",
        "Option 4":"L2-5 transverse process",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Ischial spine"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Blood supply of ureter is all except which one of the following?",
        "Option 1":"Iliolumbar",
        "Option 2":"Gonadal",
        "Option 3":"Uterine",
        "Option 4":"Renal",
        "Option 5":"Superior vesical",
        "Correct Answer":"Iliolumbar"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 42 years old woman is due to undergo left nephrectomy for a transitional cell  carcinoma involving the ureter. Which of the following structures is not related to left  ureter?",
        "Option 1":"Round ligament of uterus",
        "Option 2":"Internal iliac artery",
        "Option 3":"Ovarian artery",
        "Option 4":"Peritoneum",
        "Option 5":"Sigmoid meso-colon",
        "Correct Answer":"Round ligament of uterus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Secretion from ejaculatory duct where to go next",
        "Option 1":"Epididymis",
        "Option 2":"Vas deference (ductus deference)",
        "Option 3":"Membranous urethra",
        "Option 4":"Bulbourethral gland",
        "Option 5":"Prostatic urethra",
        "Correct Answer":"Prostatic urethra"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Superior gluteal artery arises from which vessel?",
        "Option 1":"External iliac artery",
        "Option 2":"Internal iliac artery",
        "Option 3":"femoral artery",
        "Option 4":"descending aorta",
        "Option 5":"renal artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Internal iliac artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the nerve supply to labia majora of female genitalia?",
        "Option 1":"Genital of genitofemoral nerve",
        "Option 2":"ilioinguinal nerve  *",
        "Option 3":"femoral of genitofemoral nerve",
        "Option 4":"femoral nerve",
        "Option 5":"Obturator nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"ilioinguinal nerve  *"
    },
    {
        "Question":"59 years old suffer from esophageal cancer in the lower esophagus and after  oesophagectomy for the lower 2\/3 of the esophagus. What is the arterial supply of upper  esophagus?",
        "Option 1":"left gastric artery",
        "Option 2":"short gastric artery",
        "Option 3":"descending aorta",
        "Option 4":"inferior thyroid artery",
        "Option 5":"subclavian artery",
        "Correct Answer":"inferior thyroid artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 50 years old patient is to undergo elective right hemi-colectomy for a caecal tumor;  a segment of bowel covering the caecum was held and retracted by a grasper. How will  you differentiate the jejunum from ileum?",
        "Option 1":"Narrow lumen",
        "Option 2":"Long vasa rectae",
        "Option 3":"More lymphoid tissue",
        "Option 4":"Less peritoneum",
        "Option 5":"More arterial arcade in mesentery",
        "Correct Answer":"Long vasa rectae"
    },
    {
        "Question":"inferior vesical artery is one of vessels supplying urinary bladder. The inferior vesical  artery is branch from which of the following?",
        "Option 1":"Intemal iliac artery",
        "Option 2":"External iliac artery",
        "Option 3":"Testicular artery",
        "Option 4":"Renal artery",
        "Option 5":"Femoral artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Intemal iliac artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 20 year old man is suspected of having an inflamed Mackle's diverticulum. At which  of the following locations is it most likely to be found?",
        "Option 1":"Approximately 60 cm distal to the ileo-caecal valve",
        "Option 2":"Approximately 60 cm proximal to the ileocecal valve",
        "Option 3":"Approximately 200cm distal to the ileocecal valve",
        "Option 4":"Approximately 200cm proximal to the ileocecal valve",
        "Option 5":"50cm distal to the DJ flexure",
        "Correct Answer":"Approximately 60 cm proximal to the ileocecal valve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"On exploration of abdomen on peritonitis, what is the normal location of  duodenojejunal flexure?",
        "Option 1":"On the left at transpyloric",
        "Option 2":"On the right at transpyloric",
        "Option 3":"On the right hypochondrium",
        "Option 4":"On the right iliac fossa",
        "Option 5":"On the midline",
        "Correct Answer":"On the left at transpyloric"
    },
    {
        "Question":"50 years old patient presented by mass compressing internal iliac artery. Which ls the correct anatomical relation?",
        "Option 1":"Vein is anterior to artery",
        "Option 2":"Vein is lateral to artery",
        "Option 3":"Ureter is anterior to artery",
        "Option 4":"Artery is anterior to vein",
        "Option 5":"Artery is posterior to vein",
        "Correct Answer":"Artery is anterior to vein"
    },
    {
        "Question":"When we do pringle maneuver for controlling bleeding from liver vessel Where does this vessel travel?",
        "Option 1":"Gastrohepatic ligament",
        "Option 2":"Gastrocolic ligament",
        "Option 3":"Falciform ligament",
        "Option 4":"Triangular ligament",
        "Option 5":"Linorenal ligament",
        "Correct Answer":"Gastrohepatic ligament"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Posterior relation of lower pole of the kidney includes which of the following?",
        "Option 1":"Erector spinae muscle",
        "Option 2":"Quadratus lamborum muscle",
        "Option 3":"Diaphragm",
        "Option 4":"Hepatic flexure",
        "Option 5":"Iliacus muscle",
        "Correct Answer":"Quadratus lamborum muscle"
    },
    {
        "Question":"2 years old child has retractile testis due to reflex contraction of muscle. what is the pathognomonic origin structure?",
        "Option 1":"Transversalis fascia",
        "Option 2":"Internal oblique muscle",
        "Option 3":"External oblique muscle",
        "Option 4":"Transversus abdominus muscle",
        "Option 5":"rectus abdominus muscle",
        "Correct Answer":"Internal oblique muscle"
    },
    {
        "Question":"60 years old man has inguinal swelling and after laparoscopic exploration, it was found it come medial to inferior epigastric vessels. What is the type of hernia?",
        "Option 1":"Spigelian hernia",
        "Option 2":"Direct inguinal hernia",
        "Option 3":"Indirect inguinal hernia",
        "Option 4":"Femoral hernia",
        "Option 5":"Lumbar hernia",
        "Correct Answer":"Direct inguinal hernia"
    },
    {
        "Question":"50 year old man suffered form bleeding from anus and on digital rectal examination, there is bleeding. What is the source of this bleeding?",
        "Option 1":"Celiac artery",
        "Option 2":"Superior mesenteric artery",
        "Option 3":"Middle colic artery",
        "Option 4":"Right colic artery",
        "Option 5":"Sigmoid artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Sigmoid artery"
    }
]